<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>方寸杂记 Follow Your Heart</title>
  
  
  <link href="http://tan-anran.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://tan-anran.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2021-07-25T01:42:32.677Z</updated>
  <id>http://tan-anran.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>谭安然</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Horn Tip | I16-18，A16-18</title>
    <link href="http://tan-anran.github.io/2021/07/24/Horn%20Tip%20|%20I16-18,%20A16-18/"/>
    <id>http://tan-anran.github.io/2021/07/24/Horn%20Tip%20|%20I16-18,%20A16-18/</id>
    <published>2021-07-23T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-07-25T01:42:32.677Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>  老友见面，听了一些未闻的故事。那些不起眼的平凡小事，其实是感情里的死去活来。因为那些都是把心交出、托付给对方的重量。<br />  早就听说“他人即地狱”，所以在心里喜欢一个人就够了，何必携她来这岸呢？</p><h2 id="issue-16"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#issue-16"></a> Issue 16</h2><blockquote><p><strong>The surest indicator of a great nation is represented not by the achievements of its rulers, artists, or scientists, but by the general welfare of its people.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss the extent to which you agree or disagree with the statement and explain your reasoning for the position you take. In developing and supporting your position, you should consider ways in which the statement might or might not hold true and explain how these considerations shape your position.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：是非判断类<br />  这又是一个要我们以偏概全的题目，国家可以是一个政治概念，也可以是一个地域概念。前者对应了当地政府对于公共事业的管理与决策，反映在人们的生活水平与福利上，而后者则对应了衡量这个地理位置所培养的文化中，人类文明成就的代表——决策者、艺术家、科学家的杰出贡献。讨论该问题的视角取决于我们究竟要衡量什么具体的对象，若是对于政府决策方式作出考量，那么对于上述论断的态度应该是更加积极的，因为提供公共品本就是解决市场中的无效率现象，提高社会的福利水平。但若是后者，则确实需要我们质疑，因为科学和艺术很多时候与政治是平行发展的，即便在社会动荡混乱时，仍然会有很多惊世之作的出现。</p><h2 id="issue-17"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#issue-17"></a> Issue 17</h2><blockquote><p><strong>The best way to teach — whether as an educator, employer, or parent — is to praise positive actions and ignore negative ones.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss the extent to which you agree or disagree with the claim. In developing and supporting your position, be sure to address the most compelling reasons and/or examples that could be used to challenge your position.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：敌方看法类<br />  这个话题在之前的Horn tip里面已经谈论过，只是加了一些修饰。虽然说这些限定词好像在理论上并不会直接影响模型的结果。</p><h2 id="issue-18"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#issue-18"></a> Issue 18</h2><blockquote><p><strong>Teachers’ salaries should be based on their students’ academic performance.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss the extent to which you agree or disagree with the claim. In developing and supporting your position, be sure to address the most compelling reasons and/or examples that could be used to challenge your position.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：敌方看法类<br />  在机制设计中，这相当于把教师视作代理人，将学生的学术表现视作教师努力教学后的依赖于教师努力的随机产出，是一个典型的委托代理问题。在模型的设计里，如果观测不到教师关于其教学质量的具体信息，通常委托人应该将教师的工资直接与其产出——也即学生表现相关联，只是在这种模型设定下因为不对称信息仅仅能达到次优均衡。<br />  但是，这样的表现可能太过绝对，因为学生具有很大的异质性，并且也不是所有学生都擅长于做学术或者想要一直在学术界深耕，所以在委托代理模型中教师面对的产出不确定性很高（方差很大），由此工资关联产出所带来的激励效果可能会较小。<br />  其次，学生的学术水平也并不是一个很好识别的变量，越是具体的KPI，就越容易受到KPI的诅咒，也即会扭曲教师所面对的激励，比如若规定教师工资增长必须有其学生发了多少篇什么期刊的论文，那么老师可能会专注于要求学生们成为论文生产的机器，而忽视从学生长远发展角度出发进行培养。这种教学模式无疑无法达到学校教书育人的目标。</p><h2 id="arguement-16"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#arguement-16"></a> Arguement 16</h2><blockquote><p><em>The following appeared in the summary of a study on headaches suffered by the residents of Mentia.</em><br /><strong>&quot;Salicylates are members of the same chemical family as aspirin, a medicine used to treat headaches. Although many foods are naturally rich in salicylates, for the past several decades, food-processing companies have also been adding salicylates to foods as preservatives. This rise in the commercial use of salicylates has been found to correlate with a steady decline in the average number of headaches reported by participants in our twenty-year study. Recently, food-processing companies have found that salicylates can also be used as flavor additives for foods. With this new use for salicylates, we can expect a continued steady decline in the number of headaches suffered by the average citizen of Mentia.&quot;</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you examine the stated and/or unstated assumptions of the argument. Be sure to explain how the argument depends on these assumptions and what the implications are for the argument if the assumptions prove unwarranted.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：Assumption类<br />  前面的Horn tip已经提过这道题啦。</p><h2 id="arguement-17"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#arguement-17"></a> Arguement 17</h2><blockquote><p><em>The following appeared in an editorial in a local newspaper.</em><br /><strong>&quot;Commuters complain that increased rush-hour traffic on Blue Highway between the suburbs and the city center has doubled their commuting time. The favored proposal of the motorists’ lobby is to widen the highway, adding an additional lane of traffic. Opponents note that last year’s addition of a lane to the nearby Green Highway was followed by a worsening of traffic jams on it. Their suggested alternative proposal is adding a bicycle lane to Blue Highway. Many area residents are keen bicyclists. A bicycle lane would encourage them to use bicycles to commute, it is argued, thereby reducing rush-hour traffic.&quot;</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss what questions would need to be answered in order to decide whether the recommendation and the argument on which it is based are reasonable. Be sure to explain how the answers to these questions would help to evaluate the recommendation.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：Question类<br />  前面的Horn tip又已经提过这道题啦（悄悄偷懒.jpg）。</p><h2 id="arguement-18"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#arguement-18"></a> Arguement 18</h2><blockquote><p><em>The following appeared as a recommendation by a committee planning a ten-year budget for the city of Calatrava.</em><br /><strong>&quot;The birthrate in our city is declining: in fact, last year’s birthrate was only one-half that of five years ago. Thus the number of students enrolled in our public schools will soon decrease dramatically, and we can safely reduce the funds budgeted for education during the next decade. At the same time, we can reduce funding for athletic playing fields and other recreational facilities. As a result, we will have sufficient money to fund city facilities and programs used primarily by adults, since we can expect the adult population of the city to increase.&quot;</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss what specific evidence is needed to evaluate the argument and explain how the evidence would weaken or strengthen the argument.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：Evidence类<br />  再穷也不能穷孩子呀。虽然出生率在下降，但是人口基数却可能在增加，这种情况下，新增儿童数量可能并没有减少，我们需要更多的证据表明新入学学生数量在下一个十年确实会显著地减少。<br />  此外，即便我们确实能够证明新入学学生数量在未来一段时间会显著的减小，我们仍然需要额外的证据表明我们未来的教学开支确实能够缩减。需要注意的是，即便排除通货膨胀的因素，在不同的时代，所需要学习的内容也会与时俱进，其相应所需要的开支也会增大。<br />  其次，我们也需要额外的证据表明确实有必要减少运动和其他娱乐设施的支出，我们需要弄清楚这些支出的服务对象，因为这些支出可能本身就已经是服务成人群体了。<br />  最后，我们不明确在前面过程之中节省的预算是否足够构建服务成人的项目和体系，并且我们也不能确定成人数量在多大程度上会增加，并且我们还需要注意的是，成人是一个很宽泛的概念，包含了青年、中年、老年。处在不同阶段的人群所能够参加的活动、需要的设施也会完全不一样，这意味预算的结构需要充分结构化，进而才能够判断是否完全满足城市发展的要求。</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;  老友见面，听了一些未闻的故事。那些不起眼的平凡小事，其实是感情里的死去活来。因为那些都是把心交出、托付给对方的重量。&lt;br /&gt;
  早就听说“他人即地狱”，所以在心里喜欢一个人就够了，何必携她来这岸呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;issue-16&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="GRE" scheme="http://tan-anran.github.io/categories/GRE/"/>
    
    
    <category term="钻牛角尖" scheme="http://tan-anran.github.io/tags/%E9%92%BB%E7%89%9B%E8%A7%92%E5%B0%96/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Horn Tip | I13-15，A13-15</title>
    <link href="http://tan-anran.github.io/2021/07/23/Horn%20Tip%20|%20I13-15,%20A13-15/"/>
    <id>http://tan-anran.github.io/2021/07/23/Horn%20Tip%20|%20I13-15,%20A13-15/</id>
    <published>2021-07-22T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-07-24T16:15:10.203Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>  </p><blockquote><center>"People say something with certainty, because they know too little about it."</center><p align="right">--François Pierre Guillaume Guizot</p></blockquote><h2 id="issue-13"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#issue-13"></a> Issue 13</h2><blockquote><p><strong>Governments should offer college and university education free of charge to all students.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss the extent to which you agree or disagree with the recommendation and explain your reasoning for the position you take. In developing and supporting your position, describe specific circumstances in which adopting the recommendation would or would not be advantageous and explain how these examples shape your position.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：条件型建议类<br />  感觉这其实是一个argument的题目。<br />  实现免费的大学和学院教育固然很好，能够普及教育，提高全民的受教育水平，但是这同时也财政开支很大，其来源大概率是税收。针对于全民的税收则会要求所提供的教育具有一定的全民公平性，但是并不是所有人都期望上大学。每个人都会有自己不同他人的职业发展方向，完全免费的教育并不意味着完全的公平。<br />  此外，完全免费的教育一定程度上可能会影响学院与大学之间的竞争，导致大学教育质量的下降。</p><h2 id="issue-14"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#issue-14"></a> Issue 14</h2><blockquote><p><strong>The luxuries and conveniences of contemporary life prevent people from developing into truly strong and independent individuals.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss the extent to which you agree or disagree with the statement and explain your reasoning for the position you take. In developing and supporting your position, you should consider ways in which the statement might or might not hold true and explain how these considerations shape your position.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：是非判断类<br />  题中没有限定比较对象，不确定究竟是同时代的人进行比较还是与过去的人进行比较，更有可能是后者，因为题中除开“contemporary”，其他形容词都显得非常虚无缥缈。<br />  我们想要弄明白在题目中所提出的强大而独立的个体究竟意味着什么。在过去的信息沟通手段相对匮乏，交通出行不那么便利的时候，人们可能更多地局限于自己的小世界里。若是要满足更高质量的生活追求，人们通常需要作出很大的努力，打通人脉、创造物质条件，使得自己独当一面，变得独立而自主。从这个角度来说，在受限的社会与物质环境下，更有可能磨练出强大而独立的个体。<br />  但是另一方面，相较于过去，如今的生活水平已普遍提高，交通发达、通信便利，人们走出自己的小世界仿佛已是触手可及，大部分人们也不再需要为温饱问题发愁，但是这是否意味着人们所面临的竞争已经减小，不再需要个体强大的能力了呢？欲望是无穷无尽的，生活物质的改善不过是赋予人们更多参与竞争的机会与更广大的平台。当然，过去的“强大和独立”在如今的社会自然有不同的含义。在沟通联系日益密切的社会里，我们需要更加紧密的连接在一起，术业有专攻，在相对特定的领域进行探索与开拓，对于具体的知识有充分的了解与挖掘。这亦是一种真正的独立。</p><h2 id="issue-15"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#issue-15"></a> Issue 15</h2><blockquote><p><strong>In any field of inquiry, the beginner is more likely than the expert to make important contributions.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss the extent to which you agree or disagree with the statement and explain your reasoning for the position you take. In developing and supporting your position, you should consider ways in which the statement might or might not hold true and explain how these considerations shape your position.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：是非判断类<br />  对于贡献的评判总是带有一种事后诸葛亮、以结果论英雄的感觉。科学的发展本是不断积累、不断铺垫的，正所谓“站在巨人的肩膀上”。<br />  我们需要清楚的认识到什么是“贡献”，就某一特定领域而言，领域外的人和领域内的人对于贡献的了解可能并不一样。当前各个学问的发展已经相当专业化，深耕某一领域专家更有可能充分了解自己所处领域的庞大而系统知识，专攻领域中某些在外人眼中看起来不重要但实则很关键的问题。另一方面，一中心的视角、多种学科的交叉则可能是刚刚进入一个领域的新人更有可能为这个领域所带来的，“初生牛犊不怕虎”，这种另起炉灶的贡献更加边际上更为显著，也更加容易得到发展，在社会的应用层面看起来也会更加重要，所以会给我们产生出“新手的运气”的错觉。<br />  不过，我们不能忽视的是，新人的贡献终究也是还是需要过往专家长时间的铺垫，所以从这个角度上来说，那些领域的专家也是贡献者中的一份子。</p><h2 id="arguement-13"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#arguement-13"></a> Arguement 13</h2><blockquote><p><em>The following was written as a part of an application for a small-business loan by a group of developers in the city of Monroe.</em><br /><strong>&quot;A jazz music club in Monroe would be a tremendously profitable enterprise. Currently, the nearest jazz club is 65 miles away; thus, the proposed new jazz club in Monroe, the C-Note, would have the local market all to itself. Plus, jazz is extremely popular in Monroe: over 100,000 people attended Monroe’s annual jazz festival last summer; several well-known jazz musicians live in Monroe; and the highest-rated radio program in Monroe is ‘Jazz Nightly,’ which airs every weeknight at 7 P.M. Finally, a nationwide study indicates that the typical jazz fan spends close to $1,000 per year on jazz entertainment.&quot;</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss what specific evidence is needed to evaluate the argument and explain how the evidence would weaken or strengthen the argument.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：Evidence类<br />  我们需要额外的证据来表明建一个新的爵士俱乐部能够确实带来有效的利润流。<br />  首先，最近的爵士俱乐部虽然很远，但是我们需要证据表明其对于本地的市场的占有情况、以及其顾客的黏性（比方说虽然远但是顾客愿意驾车去），进而分析建立一个新的爵士俱乐部创造的到底是一个垄断市场还是一个寡头垄断市场。<br />  其次，我们需要额外的证据说明在Monroe当地爵士音乐确实很受欢迎，在Monroe每年的爵士乐盛典及电台节目的数据中，我们并不清楚有多少数字是当地人提供的，这将影响到我们对于爵士乐俱乐部是都会在当地受欢迎的判断。<br />  最后，基于全国的调查也不能够完全代表Monroe当地的具体情况，我们不清楚本地的粉丝占比有多少，以及他们的消费力能够达到什么样的程度。需要搜集额外的证据予以支撑。</p><h2 id="arguement-14"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#arguement-14"></a> Arguement 14</h2><blockquote><p><em>The following appeared in the summary of a study on headaches suffered by the residents of Mentia</em>.<br /><strong>&quot;Salicylates are members of the same chemical family as aspirin, a medicine used to treat headaches. Although many foods are naturally rich in salicylates, for the past several decades, food-processing companies have also been adding salicylates to foods as preservatives. This rise in the commercial use of salicylates has been found to correlate with a steady decline in the average number of headaches reported by participants in our twenty-year study. Recently, food-processing companies have found that salicylates can also be used as flavor additives for foods. With this new use for salicylates, we can expect a continued steady decline in the number of headaches suffered by the average citizen of Mentia.&quot;</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss what specific evidence is needed to evaluate the argument and explain how the evidence would weaken or strengthen the argument.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：Evidence类<br />  前面的Horn tip已经提过这道题啦。</p><h2 id="arguement-15"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#arguement-15"></a> Arguement 15</h2><blockquote><p><em>The following appeared in a letter to the editor of a local newspaper.</em><br /><strong>&quot;Commuters complain that increased rush-hour traffic on Blue Highway between the suburbs and the city center has doubled their commuting time. The favored proposal of the motorists’ lobby is to widen the highway, adding an additional lane of traffic. But last year’s addition of a lane to the nearby Green Highway was followed by a worsening of traffic jams on it. A better alternative is to add a bicycle lane to Blue Highway. Many area residents are keen bicyclists. A bicycle lane would encourage them to use bicycles to commute, and so would reduce rush-hour traffic rather than fostering an increase.&quot;</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss what specific evidence is needed to evaluate the argument and explain how the evidence would weaken or strengthen the argument.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：Evidence类<br />  首先，就增加通行通道的都否定论据上，Green高速和Blue高速不一定可比，Green高速在增加一条新的机动车道后可能因为其他建设时间导致了更加糟糕的交通状况，而Blue告诉可能不会受其影响。我们需要额外的证据来说明增加新的车道确实会导致更差的交通，诸如通过模型验算、数据统计推测等。<br />  其次，我们需要额外的证据表明居住在Blue告诉附近的人们会愿意骑行车通勤。文章所说的热衷于骑行可能是站在“户外健身”运动的情形，而通勤骑行自行车可能会非常辛苦，同时还涉及到骑车速度、停车、更换衣物等诸多问题。因此即便有新的自行车通道，人们不一定愿意骑行上下班。<br />  此外，即便人们真的愿意骑行自行车，我们需要额外的证据表明岂会更加快捷而不是更加混乱，比如不会出现机动车占用自行车通道或者是自行车乱闯入机动车车道等情况，这些情形的发生会进一步扰乱交通秩序，增加通勤时间。</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&quot;People say something with certainty, because they know too little about it.&quot;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;--Fra</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="GRE" scheme="http://tan-anran.github.io/categories/GRE/"/>
    
    
    <category term="钻牛角尖" scheme="http://tan-anran.github.io/tags/%E9%92%BB%E7%89%9B%E8%A7%92%E5%B0%96/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Horn Tip | I10-12，A10-12</title>
    <link href="http://tan-anran.github.io/2021/07/22/Horn%20Tip%20|%20I10-12,%20A10-12/"/>
    <id>http://tan-anran.github.io/2021/07/22/Horn%20Tip%20|%20I10-12,%20A10-12/</id>
    <published>2021-07-21T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-07-23T04:32:50.696Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>  不知道自己的选择是对是错，只得咬着牙走下去，宁要亲眼看见结果。</p><h2 id="issue-10"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#issue-10"></a> Issue 10</h2><blockquote><p><strong>Claim: The best way to understand the character of a society is to examine the character of the men and women that the society chooses as its heroes or its role models.</strong><br /><strong>Reason: Heroes and role models reveal a society’s highest ideals.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss the extent to which you agree or disagree with the claim and the reason on which that claim is based.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：因果类<br />  就题目中的声明来说，理解一个社会的特征和理解一个社会中某个鲜明个体的特征是否有必然的联系？这两者是可以进行比较的吗？社会是如何选择它的英雄，如何选择它的代表，以至于给我们机会“以偏概全”呢？更多地，当社会与个体呈现出某种类似的特征时，可能不是社会“选择”了某一个个体，也有可能是一个个体有意识地“引导”了一个社会，其典型就是克里斯玛式的领袖，但是这种领袖的特征并不能完全说明社会本身的特征，因为社会可能更像是一种可以被塑造的材料，就像Gustave Le Bon在《乌合之众》（<em>The Crowd： A Study of the Popular Mind</em>）一书中所描绘的群众心理：冲动、易变、易受控制。<!--Le Bon claims that there are several characteristics of crowd psychology: "impulsiveness, irritability, incapacity to reason, the absence of judgement of the critical spirit, the exaggeration of sentiments, and others..."-->所以这里我们仅仅观察社会中某个偶像的特征，是很难以发现整个社会的关于其“材质”的特性的，而这些材质性质的形成不仅仅是个体性质的简单加总，更是一种令人叹为观止的协同作用。<br />  那么，针对于题中论断所给出的原因也就不攻自破了，既然社会可能会被人有意引导，那么这种引导就极有可能是正向的也有可能是负向的。我们并不能说一个偶像成功引导了社会是因为其代表着社会的最高理想，而更有可能是他的某些特征与当时社会中其他个体的情况有较好的亲和性，进而反顾来推动他/她成为社会的英雄、偶像或典型。<br />  其实这个问题有一点点像在讨论究竟是时势造英雄还是英雄造时势，对于前者而言我们有著名的老话：“站在风口上猪都会飞”；对于后者，我们总是可以拿领袖的实例来进行讨论。辩证法告诉我们，集体与个体本就是辩证统一的。</p><h2 id="issue-11"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#issue-11"></a> Issue 11</h2><blockquote><p><strong>Governments should place few, if any, restrictions on scientific research and development.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss the extent to which you agree or disagree with the recommendation and explain your reasoning for the position you take. In developing and supporting your position, describe specific circumstances in which adopting the recommendation would or would not be advantageous and explain how these examples shape your position.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：条件型建议类<br />  “科学无国界”，这是一个看起来尤为纯粹且美好的期望。但是科学中的人有自己的国籍、有自己的社会属性，没有任何一位科学家真正生活在社会/政治真空里。科学共同体似乎一直在期望自己可以摆脱自己的政治和社会属性的束缚，但是事实上很难做到，一方面是因为其通过证伪方法构造的信仰形式是当代社会所安身立命的一大根基，另一方面则是科学共同体自身的运行便依赖着逃不脱的社会形态与工具，其典型就是科学道德伦理。<br />  若把政府当做是一个科学的门外汉、局外人，那么的确从纯粹科学自身发展的角度来说，政府不能也不应该左右科学的发展，因为科学的发展方向与政府自身所服务的目标没有必然的联系。但是，若把政府作为公共品的提供者，那么其就有很多指涉科学界的责任需要承担。科学界中有一些共同需要遵守的道德伦理，单纯凭借科学共同体内部的自律和惩罚无法有效的实现，这时候就需要政府来协助完成，比如，政府可能会设置专利保护，保护科学家研发的积极性、打击伪劣盗版与剽窃等行为；也有可能会防止垄断，鼓励科学家之间的有效竞争。除此之外，科学共同体毕竟不是社会真空，其对于其他社会结构也会存在或正或负的外部性。比如政府会禁止科学未被道德伦理直接将人用作实验体等。这些措施在某种可以被视作是一种现值，但是其目标仍然是为了促进科学的良性发展与其他社会组件的良好互动。</p><h2 id="issue-12"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#issue-12"></a> Issue 12</h2><blockquote><p><strong>The best way to teach is to praise positive actions and ignore negative ones.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss the extent to which you agree or disagree with the statement and explain your reasoning for the position you take. In developing and supporting your position, you should consider ways in which the statement might or might not hold true and explain how these considerations shape your position.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：是非判断类<br />  我们知道，“胡萝卜加大棒”（Carrot and stick）是奖惩结合的代名词。虽然说但从信息集的角度来看，若没有第三种行为模式，那么“奖励”代表“行为正确”、“没有奖励”代表“行为错误”这一对应本质上与奖励正确行为、惩罚错误行为的实际效果是一样的，但是由于存在一些中庸的常规行为，所以导致孩子在学习的过程中产生混合的判断，不确定自己所做出的行为类型是属于错误行为还是常规行为，而且这一信念既有可能一直保持稳定，直至那些错误的行为日积月累酿成大祸。因此，在我们这样特定的条件下，教育最好能够明确的提供反馈来促使孩子明确区分自己不同行为的类型，进而产生自己明确而稳定的信念。<br />  不过，事实上仅仅鼓励正确行为也有其合理性，这关系着我们如何来理解“正确”与“错误”。显然，在教学中的是非判断是基于教师先验的信念。但是时代变化的很快，现在看似正确的观点在未来则有可能被证明大错特错。因此，教师仅仅鼓励孩子们的正确行为，是一种处在当下的权宜之计，既帮助孩子们区分当今社会所认可的行为，又保护了孩子们选择其他的可能性。当然，这一些论点都要基于社会对于这些行为的评判在人的生命周期中确实会产生极大变化的前提之上。</p><h2 id="arguement-10"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#arguement-10"></a> Arguement 10</h2><blockquote><p><strong>According to a recent report, cheating among college and university students is on the rise. However, Groveton College has successfully reduced student cheating by adopting an honor code, which calls for students to agree not to cheat in their academic endeavors and to notify a faculty member if they suspect that others have cheated. Groveton’s honor code replaced a system in which teachers closely monitored students; under that system, teachers reported an average of thirty cases of cheating per year. In the first year the honor code was in place, students reported twenty-one cases of cheating; five years later, this figure had dropped to fourteen. Moreover, in a recent survey, a majority of Groveton students said that they would be less likely to cheat with an honor code in place than without. Thus, all colleges and universities should adopt honor codes similar to Groveton’s in order to decrease cheating among students.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss what questions would need to be answered in order to decide whether the recommendation and the argument on which it is based are reasonable. Be sure to explain how the answers to these questions would help to evaluate the recommendation.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：Question类<br />  这实际上是将监督权力从老师下放到学生个体身上，其理想初衷是很好的，但是若从博弈论理性人的角度出发，这可能不是一个合意的选择。<br />  首先，我们需要了解Groveton College的荣誉准则系统是否确实有效果？比如这个系统是否给学生提供了检举揭发的激励。就目前文中的描述来看其并没有提供任何的激励，基于理性人的设定，学生们就更有可能合谋而不去检举揭发其他学生；而在原先的教师检举体系中，教师与学生没有利益相关，所以也更加有可能去检查学生的恶作弊行为（尽管也有可能被贿赂），因此作弊案件的减少可能不是来源于作弊人数的减少，二更有可能是来源于举报数量的减少。<br />  其次，我们需要质疑调查研究显示的学生针对荣誉准则系统的态度，如果学生的身份已经是包庇者，我们不能够确定问卷调查所询问的态度是否反映了他们真实的偏好。因为维系这个有“缺陷”的制度对于他们是有利可图的，也即更多的作弊、更好的成绩，那么他们自然会说对于这个制度的好话。<br />  最后，老调重弹，Groventon College的5年前学生情况可能与现在其他各个学校的情况并不可比。比方说原先Groventon College本身的作弊率就很高，提出这个政策才勉强达到如今的水平。文中的两个“recent”并没有告诉我们具体的时间，我们不知道其具体的变化方向为何。</p><h2 id="arguement-11"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#arguement-11"></a> Arguement 11</h2><blockquote><p>The following appeared in an article written by Dr. Karp, an anthropologist.<br /><strong>&quot;Twenty years ago, Dr. Field, a noted anthropologist, visited the island of Tertia and concluded from his observations that children in Tertia were reared by an entire village rather than by their own biological parents. However, my recent interviews with children living in the group of islands that includes Tertia show that these children spend much more time talking about their biological parents than about other adults in the village. This research of mine proves that Dr. Field’s conclusion about Tertian village culture is invalid and thus that the observation-centered approach to studying cultures is invalid as well. The interview-centered method that my team of graduate students is currently using in Tertia will establish a much more accurate understanding of child-rearing traditions there and in other island cultures.&quot;</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you examine the stated and/or unstated assumptions of the argument. Be sure to explain how the argument depends on these assumptions and what the implications are for the argument if the assumptions prove unwarranted.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：Assumption类<br />  在前一篇Horn tip已经分析过这个题目了，只是这里的导语发生了变化，变成检查其假设了，不过有一说一，感觉针对假设的话会更好讨论。（不要打脸哇！）</p><h2 id="arguement-12"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#arguement-12"></a> Arguement 12</h2><blockquote><p><strong>A recently issued twenty-year study on headaches suffered by the residents of Mentia investigated the possible therapeutic effect of consuming salicylates. Salicylates are members of the same chemical family as aspirin, a medicine used to treat headaches. Although many foods are naturally rich in salicylates, food-processing companies also add salicylates to foods as preservatives. The twenty-year study found a correlation between the rise in the commercial use of salicylates and a steady decline in the average number of headaches reported by study participants. At the time when the study concluded, food-processing companies had just discovered that salicylates can also be used as flavor additives for foods, and, as a result, many companies plan to do so. Based on these study results, some health experts predict that residents of Mentia will suffer even fewer headaches in the future.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss what questions would need to be answered in order to decide whether the prediction and the argument on which it is based are reasonable. Be sure to explain how the answers to these questions would help to evaluate the prediction.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：Question类<br />  首先，我们并没有明确的证据表明当地商业使用水杨酸盐成分的增加与当地头疼症状报告的减少有明确的英国联系，这两个情况可能都与当地经济发展、医疗条件、卫生环境改善有关，这两个因素之间可能存在伪相关关系。<br />  其次，我们并不确定水杨酸盐类成分的摄入与头痛之间是否呈现出绝对的负相关关系，比如其是否存在阈值，或者存在倒U形关系，在之前20年水杨酸盐成分的增加可能正好处于人们摄入水杨酸盐较少的一侧，而进一步增加水杨酸盐在食品中的用量不一定能够进一步减少当地的头疼症状，更有甚者，可能物极必反，产生药物中毒等情况。<br />  最后，我们不能确定食品公司所说的以芳香添加剂的形式增加水杨酸盐的使用能够确实的增加人们对于该成分的摄入。芳香添加剂的使用可能会改变水杨酸盐原本的理化性质，若是如此，可能未来人们的水杨酸盐摄入比例不会有明显的变化。</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;  不知道自己的选择是对是错，只得咬着牙走下去，宁要亲眼看见结果。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;issue-10&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;markdownIt-Anchor&quot; href=&quot;#issue-10&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Issue 10&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="GRE" scheme="http://tan-anran.github.io/categories/GRE/"/>
    
    
    <category term="钻牛角尖" scheme="http://tan-anran.github.io/tags/%E9%92%BB%E7%89%9B%E8%A7%92%E5%B0%96/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Horn Tip | I7-9，A7-9</title>
    <link href="http://tan-anran.github.io/2021/07/21/Horn%20Tip%20|%20I7-9,%20A7-9/"/>
    <id>http://tan-anran.github.io/2021/07/21/Horn%20Tip%20|%20I7-9,%20A7-9/</id>
    <published>2021-07-20T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-07-23T04:32:46.248Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>  </p><h2 id="issue-7"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#issue-7"></a> Issue 7</h2><blockquote><p><strong>Governments should focus on solving the immediate problems of today rather than on trying to solve the anticipated problems of the future.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss the extent to which you agree or disagree with the recommendation and explain your reasoning for the position you take. In developing and supporting your position, describe specific circumstances in which adopting the recommendation would or would not be advantageous and explain how these examples shape your position.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：条件型建议类<br />  应该着重于解决当下的问题还是预期的问题，这其实有一些像Issue 4中的关于政治领袖的讨论。只是这里的主体相对更加广泛一些，是一个决策团体。同样的，适用于说明改革优点的事例仍然有所侧重的支持任意一方观点。而能够这样做的主要原因则是我们对于“immediate”和“anticipated”的划分不是完全清晰的，对于“problems”一词也没有明确的定义，这都依赖于讲故事的人所想采取的立场。<br />  有意思的是，如果将这个问题的解决视作数学中的优化，那么局部最优不一定是全局最优，而全局最优一定是局部最优。这样看来好像我们应该主动倾向于选择去解决长远的预期的问题。但是事实上进行全局最优的前提是我们确实对于全局具有清晰的认知，可现实生活中我们甚至不知道我们的预期是否正确，那更何谈我们能坚信自己对未来所预期的问题及其解决方式就一定卓有成效呢？而局部最优倒似乎是现实可行的，只是又容易故步自封，所以我们市场会故意需要一些漂移、一些扰动、一些“好”的“坏”的随机性来避免完全均衡于局部最优点，一点一点逼近我们所希冀的全局有效。</p><h2 id="issue-8"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#issue-8"></a> Issue 8</h2><blockquote><p><strong>Some people believe that college students should consider only their own talents and interests when choosing a field of study. Others believe that college students should base their choice of a field of study on the availability of jobs in that field.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss which view more closely aligns with your own position and explain your reasoning for the position you take. In developing and supporting your position, you should address both of the views presented.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：两种看法类<br />  这个问题其实应该和学生们选择上大学、选一个专业究竟是为了什么有关，在目的不一致的情况下不是特别清楚应如何进行比较。<br />  当然，这个题目也有坑。就第一个观点来说，仅仅考虑天赋和兴趣似乎太过绝对了，毕竟在选择专业时进行决策所依赖的经验是过去的经验，人在真正体验事物之前，并不能完全清楚地认识到这件事情是否可能成为自己的擅长或者是兴趣，因此仅凭过去的经验做出选择，无疑扼杀了自己体验更多的可能性。虽然说，如果一个人在某些方面很早就显示出了极高的天才，那社会倒确实会给他创造工作机会。第二个观点的表述则可能相对更加中和一些，适当的参考当前提供的就业机会能够给学生们未来进行自我培养更多的启发和指引。不过我们同时也应该注意的是，教育的培养存在时滞，当前热门的行业在学生们毕业以后不一定仍然热门。<br />  我们也不应该完全以就业论英雄，实现社会价值与人生价值的方式终归是有很多种。</p><h2 id="issue-9"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#issue-9"></a> Issue 9</h2><blockquote><p><strong>Laws should be flexible enough to take account of various circumstances, times, and places.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss the extent to which you agree or disagree with the statement and explain your reasoning for the position you take. In developing and supporting your position, you should consider ways in which the statement might or might not hold true and explain how these considerations shape your position.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：是否判断类<br />  “flexible”一词就像中文“适合”一词一样，若不放在具体的语境下几乎没有完全明确的含义，而后面的“enough to”之后的内容又只是用更宽泛的词进行了一些扩充。<br />  一个完整的法律体系分为很多种不同的方面，有的部分负责立下法律的根基、明确法的精神，有的部分则负责被应用于具体的司法实践。毕竟，目前的法律是成文的，既然需要写成文字便终究难以在有限的空间中穷尽所有情况，所以法律本身应该是原则性的、提纲挈领的，而对于法条的应用与解释则可以具体问题具体分析。所以这里的法律似乎既灵活又不灵活，说它灵活是因为它的内容可以被多样解释，说不灵活是因为它的形式是固定的，两者辩证统一。（有关于大陆法系和欧美法系的区别这里就不过多讨论了）<br />  这里应该大部分只能指出正面的论据，法律的形式应该服务与它的目标，对于特别具体的法律，我们只能说担心起言多必失。</p><h2 id="arguement-7"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#arguement-7"></a> Arguement 7</h2><blockquote><p>The following is a memorandum from the business manager of a television station.<br /><strong>&quot;Over the past year, our late-night news program has devoted increased time to national news and less time to weather and local news. During this period, most of the complaints received from viewers were concerned with our station’s coverage of weather and local news. In addition, local businesses that used to advertise during our late-night news program have canceled their advertising contracts with us. Therefore, in order to attract more viewers to our news programs and to avoid losing any further advertising revenues, we should expand our coverage of weather and local news on all our news programs.&quot;</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you examine the stated and/or unstated assumptions of the argument. Be sure to explain how the argument depends on these assumptions and what the implications are for the argument if the assumptions prove unwarranted.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：Assumption类<br />  在电视台更多的放送国家新闻、更少的放送地区新闻和天气预报后，有两个现象促使管理者认为应该增加地区新闻和天气预报的放送时间，一个是观众对于地区新闻和天气预报的抱怨增加了，另一个是地区企业取消了与电台在这个时间段合作的广告合同。<br />  首先，文章假设观众抱怨的增加仅仅是因为地区新闻和天气预报时间的减少。但是我们需要注意的是，当改变了节目的播放时间，同时改变的还有节目的质量，节目可能会变得简短不够详细，这也是观众们可能会抱怨的很大理由。其次，目前没有直接的数据证据表明改变原先的播放结构对于观众人数有明显下降影响，所以即便回到原先的播放方案也不一定能够吸引更多的观众。<br />  在广告合同方面，其假设了当地新闻放送时间减少减少了当地企业签订广告合同的意愿，但是这也有可能是源于其他电视频道或者电台其他时间段节目的竞争。此外，备忘率假设了当地企业是唯一的广告来源，当增加了国家新闻放送时间的时候也有可能吸引更大的跨地区企业来投放广告，这之中我们需要进行权衡取舍。</p><h2 id="arguement-8"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#arguement-8"></a> Arguement 8</h2><blockquote><p><strong>Two years ago, radio station WCQP in Rockville decided to increase the number of call-in advice programs that it broadcast; since that time, its share of the radio audience in the Rockville listening area has increased significantly. Given WCQP’s recent success with call-in advice programming, and citing a nationwide survey indicating that many radio listeners are quite interested in such programs, the station manager of KICK in Medway recommends that KICK include more call-in advice programs in an attempt to gain a larger audience share in its listening area.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss what questions would need to be answered in order to decide whether the recommendation and the argument on which it is based are reasonable. Be sure to explain how the answers to these questions would help to evaluate the recommendation.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：Question类<br />  WCQP电台的成功经历是2年前开始的，其成功的经历可以完全复制吗？两年前的WCQP电台发展情况与当前KICK电台所面临的情况可能并不一致，比如两年前可能call-in这样的节目形式不多见，WCQP电台正好站在了行业的风口上所以取得了较大的成功。而现在这个市场的结构是什么样的，替代性如何，本地市场是否有同类的电台，这都将影响到电台改革的实际效果。<br />  国家层面的调查显示有很多观众对于call-in节目感兴趣，但这个调查中感兴趣的观众是否有较多的分布在KICK当地？国家层面的调查不能完全说明当地的情况。除此之外，感兴趣并不能代表会真正来参加，不能完全确定这部分听众的黏性为多少。</p><h2 id="arguement-9"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#arguement-9"></a> Arguement 9</h2><blockquote><p>The following appeared in an article written by Dr. Karp, an anthropologist.<br /><strong>&quot;Twenty years ago, Dr. Field, a noted anthropologist, visited the island of Tertia and concluded from his observations that children in Tertia were reared by an entire village rather than by their own biological parents. However, my recent interviews with children living in the group of islands that includes Tertia show that these children spend much more time talking about their biological parents than about other adults in the village. This research of mine proves that Dr. Field’s conclusion about Tertian village culture is invalid and thus that the observation-centered approach to studying cultures is invalid as well. The interview-centered method that my team of graduate students is currently using in Tertia will establish a much more accurate understanding of child-rearing traditions there and in other island cultures.&quot;</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss what specific evidence is needed to evaluate the argument and explain how the evidence would weaken or strengthen the argument.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：Evidence类<br />  首先，我们需要更加直接的证据判断Tertia的社会结构在20年间没有发生很大的变化，可能在Dr. Field开展田野观察的时候，Tertia的孩子确实是由村庄集体抚育的，而到如今可能发生了变化。<br />  其次，我们并不能完全判断当前孩子的成长是否没有受到村庄的集体协助，“更多地与血缘父母交流”这只能说明儿童与血缘父母交流更加密切，但是囿于他们之间的特殊关系，这似乎也是情理之中的。<br />  基于上述两点，我们不能完全否定Dr. Field的结论，更不能直接地否定观察为中心的方法。即便我们使用证据证明了访谈为中心的方法在Tertia岛上有更好的准确性，我们也需要更多的证据表明其在研究其他岛屿文化上的适用性，比如不同岛屿上的语言并不相同，并且基于文化差异，被访谈者对于自身的认知与访谈者的客体认知也会存在区别，如果语言不通，也得不到在认知相对一致情形下的沟通，这一方法必然会产生很大的误差。而观察法则可能是当时仅能采取的获取素材的方式。(此外，我们也需要证据表明Dr. Karp教授的方法已经被他的团队的研究生门充分掌握并且能够构造更精确的对于Tertia岛文化认知。)</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;issue-7&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;markdownIt-Anchor&quot; href=&quot;#issue-7&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Issue 7&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Governments should focus o</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="GRE" scheme="http://tan-anran.github.io/categories/GRE/"/>
    
    
    <category term="钻牛角尖" scheme="http://tan-anran.github.io/tags/%E9%92%BB%E7%89%9B%E8%A7%92%E5%B0%96/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Horn Tip | I4-6，A4-6</title>
    <link href="http://tan-anran.github.io/2021/07/20/Horn%20Tip%20|%20I4-6,%20A4-6/"/>
    <id>http://tan-anran.github.io/2021/07/20/Horn%20Tip%20|%20I4-6,%20A4-6/</id>
    <published>2021-07-19T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-07-23T04:32:48.384Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>  钻牛角尖第二弹！</p><h2 id="issue-4"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#issue-4"></a> Issue 4</h2><blockquote><p><strong>Some people believe that in order to be effective, political leaders must yield to public opinion and abandon principle for the sake of compromise. Others believe that the most essential quality of an effective leader is the ability to remain consistently committed to particular principles and objectives.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss which view more closely aligns with your own position and explain your reasoning for the position you take. In developing and supporting your position, you should address both of the views presented.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：两种看法类<br />  这个问题其实在宏观经济学中有非常具体的反映。具体而言，财政政策与货币政策到底应该是相机决策还是从一而终，两种不同的决策会产生非常大的区别。其中一个著名的例子是政府对待描述失业率与通货膨胀之间关系的菲利普斯曲线上。</p><!--如果在因为短期供给所导致的失业率超出自然失业率的情况下，政府事先作出声明在不超发货币的前提下降低失业率并坚决执行，那么在短期之内经济会陷入难以忍受的通货紧缩，于政府而言就极有可能是本年度经济增长业绩的大幅下滑；相反，如果政府在暗中采用了宽松的货币政策，可能在短期之类能够获得较好的经济效果但是长期中这可能意味着经济将均衡于一个更高的物价水平，并且随着政府违背信用行为的多次发生，缺乏公信力的声明可能也不再能够改变人们的通胀预期，进而丧失政策效果。（这一部分还要再检查一下）--><p>  在这道题中其实更加关键的是究竟什么是“effective”，邓小平同志曾说过：“不管黑猫白猫,捉到老鼠就是好猫。”在这里，题目的要求虽然可能不完全允许我们这样做，但是对我们自身而言这两种选项本就是一个硬币的两面，大家都是在时候才论英雄。就前一种观点而言，每一个因为破旧立新而功成名就的领袖都可以成为典型，如毛主席的“农村包围城市，武装夺取政权”、罗斯福的新政等等；对于后一种观点来说，则要突出领导者对于一个长远而明智原则的始终坚持，虽然说通常而言这样的领导者不容易在历史上留下名字，因为通常是克里斯玛型领导者引发社会的狂热。但其实在现实的改革中不乏立场坚定的领导者力排众议、强忍改革过程中的阵痛，最后收获成功，典型代表包括秦孝公等。<br />  只是这里觉得又很荒诞，其实都是破旧立新，而哪一次改革又不会有需要妥协或者是饱受争议的地方呢？同一件事两个论点都能作为论据，而似乎通常而言我们对领袖的评价就是看这个改革措施最后是否真的能带来社会的福利，而改革的成功不仅仅要求决策的正确、要求领袖自身坚定地立场，还需要他对实际的把握和强大的政治智慧。总而言之，我觉得这是一个很怪的题目，就不敢继续碎碎念了。</p><h2 id="issue-5"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#issue-5"></a> Issue 5</h2><blockquote><p><strong>Formal education tends to restrain our minds and spirits rather than set them free.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss the extent to which you agree or disagree with the statement and explain your reasoning for the position you take. In developing and supporting your position, you should consider ways in which the statement might or might not hold true and explain how these considerations shape your position.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：是非判断类<br />  这个话题可是太大了，甚至还有“spirits”和“free”这样的词眼。尝试着瞎写一下。<br />  人类一直在探寻教育的终极形式，记起很久以前有一个段子是说，一个母亲接小学第一天上学的女儿放学回家，第二天就把老师告上法庭，原因是她的女儿不再将“圆”富有想象地认作是太阳、是苹果、是湖，而是老师口中教导的“圆”，她认为老师不应该如此边扼杀了汉子的想象力。事实上这甚至引发了一个更深次的话题，即是说我们应该如何教导——或者说在多大程度上向学生们展示当代社会的理性。这些所称为“圆”的知识，是我们文明的成就，也是人类感性的共同妥协，它服务于人类、也服务于自己。一个圆当然可以指代各种各样的事物，但是我们在作出这个指代、使用这个陈述的时候，确实是“圆”这个称谓是最方便、最快捷亦是最清晰的。但是我们若仅限于传输此类知识，便真正会导致扼杀孩童们的天性，也就是那些理性所依赖的发源地，感官、想象与天才。<br />  确实如此，当理性服务于自身的时候更多时，它就越像一个无法控制的野马拽着人东奔西跑。只是，正如前文所述，我们的教育并不仅仅只是传输这类知识，一个理想的教育自然是不希望孩子们成为“具体知识”的奴隶，而是希望他们能成为操控知识积木的人、理性逻辑的建造师与设计者。那些具体的知识能够随着学生们的机灵而绘成精彩的杰作，进而又被理性所规训，成为具体知识的一部分，成为一块崭新的积木，这便是我们人们文明进步的动力学。<br />  回到题目来说，正式教育究竟是限制还是解放我们的思想，这要看教育的具体形式是什么，以及教育是否能充分满足学生“人性”的要求。虽然说以教导爱弥儿方式来教导的教学方法几乎没有成功的案例（其实要看到底如何定义成功。）但是就现代教育而言，我们通常的教育还是尽量趋向于多元化的激发而非单方向的灌输，稍有个别的案例、或者更加隐性的、其实是社会的资本结构让学生们自行的妥协。毕竟，思想的解放从短期的功利上来说，“有什么用呢”？</p><h2 id="issue-6"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#issue-6"></a> Issue 6</h2><blockquote><p><strong>The well-being of a society is enhanced when many of its people question authority.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss the extent to which you agree or disagree with the statement and explain your reasoning for the position you take. In developing and supporting your position, you should consider ways in which the statement might or might not hold true and explain how these considerations shape your position.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：是非判断类<br />  可以从很多角度来理解什么是“well-being”，什么是“authority”。<br />  事实上，一个社会并不必然有一个明确具象的权威代表，而社会的福利也有很多复杂的定义。还是回到经济学中，Arrow曾在《社会选择与个人价值》（<em>Social Choice and Individual Values</em>）一书中使用集合论等数学方法证明一个满足诸多合意假设的社会必然会是独裁的，这个定理便是著名的阿罗不可能定理，在福利经济学领域引发了很大的轰动。但其实”独裁“这个概念似乎在西方观点中是最应该被抨击的，可是它却可能代表着一个相对合意的社会模型，而这亦是这一理论的魅力之处。<br />  当然，上述说法可能扯远了，就对通常质疑权威这一概念来说，这意味社会之中的大部分人是清醒的、自知的，愿意为社会福利的改进而作出努力的，也说明社会中存在这样一批人有能力清醒、意识到权威的所在。从精神层面上来说，这必然是一种社会不可多得的福气。但不过于我而言，福利的改进始终还是需依赖于物质的基础，并且，福利改善的前提一定是它的人民确确实实认识到了权威真正的属性与根本，而非只是受到狂热的鼓吹而跟风，成为怀疑论的猜忌或者是反智，若是这般，那可真将是一场再难。</p><h2 id="arguement-4"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#arguement-4"></a> Arguement 4</h2><blockquote><p>The following appeared as part of an article in a business magazine.<br /><strong>&quot;A recent study rating 300 male and female Mentian advertising executives according to the average number of hours they sleep per night showed an association between the amount of sleep the executives need and the success of their firms. Of the advertising firms studied, those whose executives reported needing no more than 6 hours of sleep per night had higher profit margins and faster growth. These results suggest that if a business wants to prosper, it should hire only people who need less than 6 hours of sleep per night.&quot;</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you examine the stated and/or unstated assumptions of the argument. Be sure to explain how the argument depends on these assumptions and what the implications are for the argument if the assumptions prove unwarranted.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：Assumption类<br />  其实晚上的睡眠时间并不能完全代表一个人的日常睡眠时间，毕竟中国人时常会有午睡的习惯。<br />  睡眠时间短只是一种现象，可能源自于其非常自律，文章直接假设了睡眠时间短的现象可以带来更高的企业产出，这实际上是有些本末倒置了。<br />  此外，被研究对象的企业不一定可比，他们的公司很有可能分别处于不同的阶段，并且需要注意的是研究结果比较的是利润率和增长率，但是这些都是成长型企业的特征，而在企业的成长期企业领导者通常会忙于商业扩张，压力很大而减少睡眠时间，而对于相对成熟的企业的企业领导者，其公司各项规章制度已经建立完善，拥有相对充足的睡眠时间也是理所应当的，上述逻辑存在内生性的问题。此外，横向来看，这也可能与企业的行业有关，不同行业的竞争压力有别，利润率与增长率自然也会不一样，不能完全归结于人自身的原因。</p><h2 id="arguement-5"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#arguement-5"></a> Arguement 5</h2><blockquote><p>The following memorandum is from the business manager of Happy Pancake House restaurants.<br /><strong>&quot;Recently, butter has been replaced by margarine in Happy Pancake House restaurants throughout the southwestern United States. This change, however, has had little impact on our customers. In fact, only about 2 percent of customers have complained, indicating that an average of 98 people out of 100 are happy with the change. Furthermore, many servers have reported that a number of customers who ask for butter do not complain when they are given margarine instead. Clearly, either these customers do not distinguish butter from margarine or they use the term ‘butter’ to refer to either butter or margarine.&quot;</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss one or more alternative explanations that could rival the proposed explanation and explain how your explanation(s) can plausibly account for the facts presented in the argument.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：Explanation类<br />  首先，就上述现象而言，我们并不能确定需要黄油的顾客占总顾客的比例，可能在美国西南部餐厅中，顾客对于黄油的需求量本身就很小。黄油需求量小，自然感知到这一改变的顾客也会很少。另一方面，我们不确定餐厅是否有合适的反馈渠道，大部分人还是倾向于”沉默“而非直接抱怨。所以，当统计数据显示只有2%的顾客抱怨时，并不能说明剩下98%的顾客都对于这个改变是满意的。<br />  其次，针对餐厅提供人造黄油给顾客但顾客仍认为是黄油的现象，其实这与顾客对餐厅的信赖程度有关。顾客不一定是食品材料领域的专家，本身也会更加倾向于依靠餐厅所给的直接印象。基于餐厅给他们所建立的“这就是黄油”的第一印象，当他们感受到人造黄油的不同口感时，更可能是认为菜品或菜谱发生了改变，而更少的倾向于直接考察黄油本身。但是当他们真正发现这一点，便极有可能会以欺诈消费者为由控告餐厅。</p><h2 id="arguement-6"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#arguement-6"></a> Arguement 6</h2><blockquote><p>The following appeared in a memorandum from the manager of WWAC radio station.<br /><strong>&quot;To reverse a decline in listener numbers, our owners have decided that WWAC must change from its current rock-music format. The decline has occurred despite population growth in our listening area, but that growth has resulted mainly from people moving here after their retirement. We must make listeners of these new residents. We could switch to a music format tailored to their tastes, but a continuing decline in local sales of recorded music suggests limited interest in music. Instead we should change to a news and talk format, a form of radio that is increasingly popular in our area.&quot;</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss what specific evidence is needed to evaluate the argument and explain how the evidence would weaken or strengthen the argument.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：Evidence类<br />  这个备忘率认为应做两项改革：1、有针对性的增加适合迁移听众口味的音乐播放来锁定这部分群体；2、因录制音乐在本地销售情况处于下降趋势反映了人们对音乐的热衷程度在下降，应该增加新闻和脱口秀类节目。<br />  首先，我们需要证据说明受众范围的扩大确实来源于退休人群的迁移。因为退休人群是一个很特殊的群体，这通常可能以为着年龄较高，并且跟随电台已经很长时间，我们需要证据表明他们对于电台的忠诚度。否则擅自改变音乐风格可能会导致这部分群体的流失。<br />  其次，我们需要更多的证据表明音乐类节目的受欢迎程度在下降，录制音乐的本地销售额减小可能是人们在音乐付费购买行为减少过程中的一个普遍现象，这种现象的产生很有可能是来源于电台类节目音乐播放的可替代性。<br />  最后，我们需要更多的证据表明转变为新闻和脱口秀节目是有利可图的，电台形式的改变势必会减少原先音乐节目放送的时间，从而改变听众对于电台的定位，这同样可能会流失一部分观众；并且，当前在本地市场中越来越受欢迎的新闻脱口秀类节目不一定完全符合当前电台的受众所在区域越来越广泛的情况；再者，可能原先本地新闻类电台就很少，如果当前电台作出了改变，会进一步改变这一市场结构，从而使得各个电台之间产生可替代性，进而利润空间压缩。</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;  钻牛角尖第二弹！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;issue-4&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;markdownIt-Anchor&quot; href=&quot;#issue-4&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Issue 4&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some people believ</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="GRE" scheme="http://tan-anran.github.io/categories/GRE/"/>
    
    
    <category term="钻牛角尖" scheme="http://tan-anran.github.io/tags/%E9%92%BB%E7%89%9B%E8%A7%92%E5%B0%96/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Horn Tip | I1-3，A1-3</title>
    <link href="http://tan-anran.github.io/2021/07/19/Horn%20Tip%20|%20I1-3,%20A1-3/"/>
    <id>http://tan-anran.github.io/2021/07/19/Horn%20Tip%20|%20I1-3,%20A1-3/</id>
    <published>2021-07-18T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-07-23T04:32:49.405Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>  感觉备考GRE是一个尤为需要耐力的长跑。而作文部分又尤为玄妙。因此希望能每天把看题的一点点想法写在这里，也并没有什么真实的依据只顾着钻牛角尖，不知道钻对没有…先这样试试看吧</p><h2 id="issue-1"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#issue-1"></a> Issue 1</h2><blockquote><p><strong>Universities should require every student to take a variety of courses outside the student’s field of study.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss the extent to which you agree or disagree with the claim. In developing and supporting your position, be sure to address the most compelling reasons and/or examples that could be used to challenge your position.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：敌方看法类<br />  其实这个问题和专业教育与通识教育之争有一些异曲同工。传统的专业教育从现代学科分类的角度出发，希望通过系统的课程体系培养让学生充分了解到一个学科发展的前沿，进而成为科学界或者产业界中的可用之材。但站在通识教育的角度，大学不仅仅是学生学习专业知识、提升专业素养的地方，同时也是学生之所真正学成为“人”、迈向社会的关键阶梯。通过要求修习多种课程让学生们从不同学科中汲取养分，不仅仅是让学生们了解当下人类社会的文明成就，更是让同学们了解和挖掘自身。<br />  另一方面，现在的各个学科之间呈现出交叉融合的倾向，来自其他学科的见解时常对于学生们自身专业的修习有很大的帮助。就像“经济学帝国主义”一词所言，经济学分析的骨骼可以延伸到各个社会科学领域。自博弈论发展以来，各种社会科学中所归纳、论证的社会现象越来越多地被经济学家使用微观机制工具加以剖析、计算与预测，尽管大部分情况下我们仍然过分的依赖严格的数学假设，但在很多时候仍取得了不错的效果。<br />  但值得注意的是，这些论证的前提均是学校对于学生额外课程的设置确实能够满足通识教育或交叉学科的培养要求。事实上，通识教育、交叉学科的培养由于其不是一个具体“专业”，所以必无法拥有像传统专业教育那样系统而完善的体系。在这种环境下，学生的自我修行更多的可能是事前自为的，而非事后规范的。换句话说，一个通才的产生要求天时地利人和，是可遇而不可求的。因此，如果学生们若是不能完全明确自身的培养目标为何，就很容易产生机制设计目标与激励效果不一致的问题：诸如不认真对待额外专业的课程，仅仅将其视作刷分提高绩点的工具，甚至更有可能陷入目标的迷失，不知道自己究竟在学什么。<br />  因此，也许通识教育的确是一种大学教育日臻完善的可能，但是它对于我们的学生的自我定位与自我认知也产生了很高的要求。如果我们没有更多相应的配套措施，往往更加容易产生事与愿违的情况。而那些配套措施的成本与真正实现通识教育的收益则又是一个需要在具体情境下权衡取舍的问题了。</p><h2 id="issue-2"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#issue-2"></a> Issue 2</h2><blockquote><p><strong>A nation should require all of its students to study the same national curriculum until they enter college.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss your views on the policy and explain your reasoning for the position you take. In developing and supporting your position, you should consider the possible consequences of implementing the policy and explain how these consequences shape your position.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：结果型建议类<br />  对于这一问题的讨论需要回答这些同一的课程体系目标为何、是什么、对于修习其他课程是否有限制，以及各个地区人才培养的现状是如何等诸多问题。<br />  就直觉上而言，采取具体问题具体分析的立场应是上选。但若说国家所要求的的课程是学生们在未来学习、工作之中所必备的技能，推广同一课程体系的目的在于全方位的提高全体国民素质，这似乎也是情理之中的。统一课程体系可以涵盖在任何工作之中都会使用的阅读、计算等多方面的素质教育。国家统一的要求执行能够倒逼教育资源相对匮乏的地区有目标有针对性的进行改革，进而提升当地的教育质量。当然其前提是国家确实能够为这些地区调配到足够的教育辅助。此外，一些关系到国家、社会稳定的内容也可以涵盖于统一课程体系之中，比如安全健康与急救等课程，这些课程的推广能够让学生们在未来更好的处理发生在自己身边的安全突发事件，这对于增强全民的安全保障意识都有非常关键的作用。<br />  不过，我们同样需要注意的是，教育本身就应是因材施教，统一的课本统一的教材不应该完全替代学生的多样化发展。各个地区生活环境、职能分工不一样，学生们对于自身所处环境的认知和未来的方向也会有所不同。如果仅仅是强制性的要求学生们修习完全一样的课程，虽然能够促进统一的竞争，但是其中一个最大的问题就是在高中结束以后不知道自己未来所努力的方向，而那个时候最快解决问题的方法就是屈从于现实，选择自己虽然不那么感兴趣但是出路较好的方向，而这又会进一步引发在某些行业竞争过剩，某些行业缺乏竞争的空心病；除此之外，由于不同地区对于现实的理解不一样，学生们对于知识的理解也会有很大差别，如果没有配套的教育资源，那么这反而可能事倍功半的进一步加大了教育差距。<br />  因此，我们所推广的统一教育从最为易行的角度而言初衷是提高国民素质，但是其要求有配套的基础设施，并且，这种教育体系不应该成为学生们多元发展的阻碍。相反，这种课程体系应该鼓励同学们积极进行自我探索、教导他们探索世界、改造世界的方法，给他们提供无限的发展可能，而不是仅仅强调具体知识的掌握。授人以鱼不如授人以渔。</p><h2 id="issue-3"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#issue-3"></a> Issue 3</h2><blockquote><p><strong>Educational institutions should actively encourage their students to choose fields of study that will prepare them for lucrative careers.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss the extent to which you agree or disagree with the claim. In developing and supporting your position, be sure to address the most compelling reasons and/or examples that could be used to challenge your position.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：敌方看法类<br />  对于这个问题我们应该有很鲜明的立场，但题目却要求我们从敌方角度来思考我们论据的薄弱点。不赞成题目论断的主要原因有三，一个是教育存在时滞，而产业的发展又是瞬息万变的，当前看上去利润丰富的行业在未来不一定仍然存在很高的劳动回报，如果在当前盲目进行教育扩张可能会导致这些领域人才过剩，另一些领域人才匮乏的情况；另一方面，学生们各有自身的学习特点与兴趣，不是所有的学生都适合学习某种特定的专业，揠苗助长只能颗粒无收；最后，职业发展并不是一个学生作为一个人的全部目标，而且获利丰富的行业也不一定真正对社会有益，而教育是一种公共事业，应该从人类与社会福祉的角度出发来考虑这个问题。<br />  站在对立方的角度，对于我们论据一的反驳主要是虽然产业发展速度很快，但是我们的教育也在时刻进行着改革，从宏观全局出发的教育体系对于未来产业的发展有一定的预见性，只要对于学生的培养是有针对的，那么学生的职业发展方向也会与时俱进。对于论据二，产业的增长点通常不止一个，并且产业之间也是息息相关的，每个人总是能够在适当高利润行业中找到自己的位置。对于论据三，某个行业的高利润代表了其行业非竞争性或其他高溢价的产业特征，这种特征反映了社会对于这方面人才的旺盛需求，当然，前提教育机构所引导的行业主要是合规合法的行业。（虽然我觉得反驳得毫无力度但是姑且先这么写吧…）</p><h2 id="arguement-1"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#arguement-1"></a> Arguement 1</h2><blockquote><p><strong>The council of Maple County, concerned about the county’s becoming overdeveloped, is debating a proposed measure that would prevent the development of existing farmland in the county. But the council is also concerned that such a restriction, by limiting the supply of new housing, could lead to significant increases in the price of housing in the county. Proponents of the measure note that Chestnut County established a similar measure ten years ago, and its housing prices have increased only modestly since. However, opponents of the measure note that Pine County adopted restrictions on the development of new residential housing fifteen years ago, and its housing prices have since more than doubled. The council currently predicts that the proposed measure, if passed, will result in a significant increase in housing prices in Maple County.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss what questions would need to be answered in order to decide whether the prediction and the argument on which it is based are reasonable. Be sure to explain how the answers to these questions would help to evaluate the prediction.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：Question类<br />  咋呼一看这个里面坑有不少，首先我们并不能确定这三个城市的房地产市场在多大程度上可以进行类比，如果其本身市场环境不相似，比如一些城市倾向于寡头市场，另一些城市倾向于完全竞争市场，那么就算是政府实施相对一致的政策也不一定会产生类似的效果。<br />  其次，C城市十年前颁布了类似的措施，但是其房价只有小幅上升，而P市在十五年前对新增住房市场进行限制，导致其房价相比于之前上升到近2倍。这一比较性论据中有两点需要讨论，一个是对新增住房市场的约制政策可以类比当前对于农村土地的约制政策吗，为什么议会无视前者非常相似政策的实施效果而选择采用不同领域的效果呢？另一个是这两个房价变化的参照点不同，前者是10年前，后者是15年前，而在前15到前10年之间是否存在因为其他原因导致普遍的房价上涨现象？这些都是不得而知的。需要获得更多的事实证据才可继续推论。</p><h2 id="arguement-2"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#arguement-2"></a> Arguement 2</h2><blockquote><p><strong>Fifteen years ago, Omega University implemented a new procedure that encouraged students to evaluate the teaching effectiveness of all their professors. Since that time, Omega professors have begun to assign higher grades in their classes, and overall student grade averages at Omega have risen by 30 percent. Potential employers, looking at this dramatic rise in grades, believe that grades at Omega are inflated and do not accurately reflect student achievement; as a result, Omega graduates have not been as successful at getting jobs as have graduates from nearby Alpha University. To enable its graduates to secure better jobs, Omega University should terminate student evaluation of professors.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss what specific evidence is needed to evaluate the argument and explain how the evidence would weaken or strengthen the argument.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：Evidence类<br />  这其实在经济学中是一个典型的信号发送模型。在题目的设定下，我们首先需要证据确定学生们的绩点通胀确实源自于教授们为了获得高评语而故意无差别给同学们高分；事实上，也有可能是教授们为了获得更好的评语，被激励而改善了自身教学方法，也使得同学们更好的吸收课程知识，进而获得了更好的成绩。学生们成绩的提高可能是来自于教学改革的成功。<br />  其次，我们需要证据证明雇主确实是因为发现了O学校学生绩点通胀以后才开始给学生的表现进行折扣。因为也许O学校与A学校在O学校开始教学评估政策开始之前就存在很大的就业水平差距，如果如此，那么O学校学生的就业水平相对较低可能不完全来源于其政策效果。两学校情况不一定具备可比性。<br />  最后，若上述逻辑悉数成立。我们仍然需要证据证明当前取消教学评估确实能够使得学生成绩反映真实情况，并且雇主不会因为O学校学生成绩的大幅下滑而进一步给O学校学生更大的惩罚。</p><h2 id="arguement-3"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#arguement-3"></a> Arguement 3</h2><blockquote><p><strong>In an attempt to improve highway safety, Prunty County last year lowered its speed limit from 55 to 45 miles per hour on all county highways. But this effort has failed: the number of accidents has not decreased, and, based on reports by the highway patrol, many drivers are exceeding the speed limit. Prunty County should instead undertake the same kind of road improvement project that Butler County completed five years ago: increasing lane widths, resurfacing rough highways, and improving visibility at dangerous intersections. Today, major Butler County roads still have a 55 mph speed limit, yet there were 25 percent fewer reported accidents in Butler County this past year than there were five years ago.</strong><br /><em>Write a response in which you discuss what specific evidence is needed to evaluate the argument and explain how the evidence would weaken or strengthen the argument.</em></p></blockquote><p>归类：Evidence类<br />  首先，我们需要证据证明，限速政策对于交通事故的发生没有任何实质上的减轻影响。虽然目前事实显示交通数量没有减少并且很多司机超速驾驶，但是交通事故的危害程度在政策前后可能发生变化，并且司机等从业者完全适应政策也需要一定时间。<br />  其次，感觉对于这种题目而言，是否可以类比都是一个必问的问题。我们需要证据说明P国家当今的铁路交通发展情况与B国家五年前的铁路交通发展状况是类似的，这样建议才有可以被讨论的空间。这种相似包括P城市的道路确实还能够进行改进、道路确实需要加宽等。<br />  第三，我们需要证据说明，B国家的交通事故减少确实是因为5年前的道路改良计划而非其他，比如B国家可能管控了交通事故的披露程度，也有可能是其他交通工具的发展产生了替代作用使得铁路不再完全受欢迎等。</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;  感觉备考GRE是一个尤为需要耐力的长跑。而作文部分又尤为玄妙。因此希望能每天把看题的一点点想法写在这里，也并没有什么真实的依据只顾着钻牛角尖，不知道钻对没有…先这样试试看吧&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;issue-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;markdownIt-Anchor</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="GRE" scheme="http://tan-anran.github.io/categories/GRE/"/>
    
    
    <category term="钻牛角尖" scheme="http://tan-anran.github.io/tags/%E9%92%BB%E7%89%9B%E8%A7%92%E5%B0%96/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>记你们的毕业</title>
    <link href="http://tan-anran.github.io/2021/07/15/%E8%AE%B0%E4%BD%A0%E4%BB%AC%E7%9A%84%E6%AF%95%E4%B8%9A/"/>
    <id>http://tan-anran.github.io/2021/07/15/%E8%AE%B0%E4%BD%A0%E4%BB%AC%E7%9A%84%E6%AF%95%E4%B8%9A/</id>
    <published>2021-07-14T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-07-15T18:08:13.734Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>  夏天，又是一届毕业季。<br />  今年的毕业季显得格外热闹，许多同级的、非同级的朋友都拉伙儿合照。说来奇怪，原本是不爱凑热闹的人，却不知怎的从很早开始就参与其中了：看着大家答辩、跑材料、整理物品、在毕业典礼上热泪盈眶、合影留念、聚会宿醉，然后珍重道别。这一切都显得很自然、很完满。就像同心的涟漪圈圈扩散，只留着水中央悠悠荡荡、平平缓缓。那些也似我全都经历过一样。想草率地说声保重，但其实要说不伤感还真是很难。那些日后再见的承诺，又有多少能兑现呀。<br />  我们似乎总是喜欢一些确定的事物，那些所谓确定性的存在让我们觉得安全而有所凭依。我们需要确定的，不仅仅是那些物质的现实，还有我们的想法、观点与态度，就即便是面对一对没有办法在短时间内决出胜负的选项，我们似乎也宁愿持着一个不去选择的确定想法来保护自己。换言之，拖延症就是一种典型吧。只要一直持有着可以自由选择的权利，就似乎总是有退路可走。可其实，终究还是没有去承担选择的后果的勇气，不然便不会有破釜沉舟的佳话了。<br />  我一直都知道自己是很幼稚的人，但是确实也不是那么明白自己真正幼稚在何处。也许写这种“矫情无脑”的文字就是一个明显表现罢。但是，这些想法和心绪一旦产生，我便很难对它们置之不理。就大家通称的“世俗”而言，我有时候尤为危险而自大地睥睨一些被奉之为圭臬的具体知识，只觉得更重要的是掌握其一以贯之的方法或脉络。但仔细想来，这又似乎与之前所偏信的“理性发端于分类”的观点有些矛盾。就像是在说骨骼固然精干，但始终需要血肉作为其组合与填充。此外，在这个被理性所统治的社会，似乎也确实更多地需要的是关于内容的不断复制、迭代与更新，来填充那些已经硕大无比的梦幻骨架。所以是不是其实在很多时候，那能希望在社会关系中占据主导地位的人会有意识地要求其他人放弃对那些理性骨架的觊觎，而逼迫他们自行淹泡在那些内容的加工制造里呢？因为只要自己把握住了关键的结构，在与其他人的协作中便不至于出现太大的乱子，只要拥有了骨架的确定性，便能够去安全的支配他者。<br />  那么，是不是其实我现在正在写的这些所谓“矫情”的文字，也正是因为它们都置身于无边无际的想象空间之中，所以被人习惯性的害怕非确定性而“太长不看”。再细小的错误，在感性的潮水里都会澎湃起来。社会只需要纯粹的故事、纯粹的热闹、纯粹的瓜、纯粹的观点，其他的毛茸茸的情感是可有可无的、需要被质疑的、不可被信任的。就单纯只是因为那些情感其实我们自己也都深深地保有。只是我们想隐藏它们，害怕放在阳光下讨论。我们在公共空间之中所抛弃的就是我们自身。<br />  当然，这样说或许也太过绝对。只不过真正的成长可能就是要去学会放弃那些给自己选择权的机会。所以当与友朋们告别后，继续泰然前行吧。<br />  烈酒与风会继续陪伴你。</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;  夏天，又是一届毕业季。&lt;br /&gt;
  今年的毕业季显得格外热闹，许多同级的、非同级的朋友都拉伙儿合照。说来奇怪，原本是不爱凑热闹的人，却不知怎的从很早开始就参与其中了：看着大家答辩、跑材料、整理物品、在毕业典礼上热泪盈眶、合影留念、聚会宿醉，然后珍重道别。这一切都显得</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="记" scheme="http://tan-anran.github.io/categories/%E8%AE%B0/"/>
    
    
    <category term="有一说一" scheme="http://tan-anran.github.io/tags/%E6%9C%89%E4%B8%80%E8%AF%B4%E4%B8%80/"/>
    
    <category term="太长不看" scheme="http://tan-anran.github.io/tags/%E5%A4%AA%E9%95%BF%E4%B8%8D%E7%9C%8B/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>欢迎光临，方寸杂记</title>
    <link href="http://tan-anran.github.io/2021/07/13/%E6%AC%A2%E8%BF%8E%E5%85%89%E4%B8%B4/"/>
    <id>http://tan-anran.github.io/2021/07/13/%E6%AC%A2%E8%BF%8E%E5%85%89%E4%B8%B4/</id>
    <published>2021-07-12T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-07-19T17:04:29.127Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>  非常感谢您的到来，这里是方寸杂记。<br />  以大家的观点来看，可能这里大多是一些些散漫空泛的片语。至于为什么要记下，其实便只因它们代表着那些生发它们的、那些我暗自想要努力抓住的时刻。<br />  对于几年前就因种种原因退出朋友圈的人而言，一个无暴力的话语空间总是可遇不可求的。尽管所谓的暴力也只是一种没有明说的要求：将生活中的事情在朋友圈里广而告之，便是期盼着有人浏览、有人关注、有人点赞。<br />  只是，我们有时候内心深处可能也并没有什么上述期待。耐心编辑、修改、发布，只是一种自我的证成，一种心愿的完毕。有人看也好，无人观也罢。有一点像写日记的心情，但是又不甘于让文字们仅仅躺在书堆里，所以这个杂记便应运而生了。<br />  心血来潮花了两天时间搭建了这个方寸之地。非常感谢Cofess提供的<a href="https://blog.cofess.com/2017/11/01/hexo-blog-theme-pure-usage-description.html">pure</a>模板，可能未来再考虑进行一些适合自己的改动，目前因为技术上的原因，能大概推送这样可已经是费了不少脑筋。<br />  虽然说，对于一个无名而自由的独立个体，不能也不应留下些什么，但既然有一个这样小而安静的地方，那就拜托大家允许我的碎碎念吧。<br />  在这个阳光灿烂的世界里，请尽情走一走、看一看。未知的东西，还多着哩。</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;  非常感谢您的到来，这里是方寸杂记。&lt;br /&gt;
  以大家的观点来看，可能这里大多是一些些散漫空泛的片语。至于为什么要记下，其实便只因它们代表着那些生发它们的、那些我暗自想要努力抓住的时刻。&lt;br /&gt;
  对于几年前就因种种原因退出朋友圈的人而言，一个无暴力的话语空间</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="迎" scheme="http://tan-anran.github.io/categories/%E8%BF%8E/"/>
    
    
    <category term="欢迎词" scheme="http://tan-anran.github.io/tags/%E6%AC%A2%E8%BF%8E%E8%AF%8D/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
